acrwebsite.org 2018-12-15

# Association For Consumer Research Website Privacy Policy | ACR

**This policy was last updated May 2018**

The Association for Consumer Research (“ACR”) has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our strong commitment to privacy. ACR is deeply committed to respecting and protecting your right to privacy and takes your privacy seriously. We have very strict privacy policies and we strive to keep your personal and financial information secure. To that end, we have prepared this privacy policy to disclose and describe our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website.

Most of all, we value your privacy . We do not sell, rent, loan, or give your email address or other personal information to anybody and will never do so.

**Collection of your Personal Information**

You can visit most pages on our site without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this privacy policy explains data collection and use in those situations. Please read the complete ACR privacy policy below in conjunction with our Terms and Conditions.

This privacy policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information that we collect when you are on our site, and when you use our services. A link on the membership page allows members to contact ACR to have their information removed.

  * We pledge to hold all information you provide to us in absolute privacy.
  * We will NEVER sell or rent your name or personal information to any third party without your express permission.
  * We NEVER sell or rent our mailing list.
  * Only authorized employees may access your information.
  * All employees are required to adhere to our strict privacy policies and any employee who violates the privacy policy is subject to termination and other disciplinary measures, up to being criminally prosecuted for their violation

**ACR’s Social Media (Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter Pages)**

ACR maintains three social media pages none of which collect/store any personal user information or track users in any way. Participants are free to join/subscribe and leave/unsubscribe at any time as they with a clicking on “leave the group” or “subscribe from the page” links associated with respective social media pages/accounts.  

**Journal of the Association for Consumer Research  (JACR)**

The files ACR sends to University of Chicago Press (UCP) for the JACR issue mailing are deleted from UCP’s email and servers.  UCP does not save that information. ACR member data for the purpose of issue claims processing is kept in a secure database.  Per General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) data retention policies that we now follow, we will erase any personally identifiable information for all records that have not been updated for three years.

**ACR Publications – Conference & Proceedings  
**  
Recording and Sharing Policy: ACR Conferences provide a forum for scholars to share unpublished work in progress that has not yet received the full scrutiny of a journal review process. Taking photos or slides or otherwise recording, duplicating, or sharing voice or visual content requires explicit and advance permission of the presenter  Conference attendee registration requires each registrant to give permission to ACR to share their name and contact information to exhibitors.

**ACR-L**

Listserv subscribers can unsubscribe at any time following explicit and straightforward instructions provided in each posting/message disseminated via ACR-L. The only data that are being recorded are subscribers’ first names, last names and email addresses which are automatically deleted once a Listerv user opts to unsubscribe from the list to stop receiving postings

**Use of Your Personal Information**

If you decide to become a member, you will receive a short series of orientation emails from ACR. From time to time, members may receive notification of new services, changes to policies or price adjustments. We will not send you other email at the address you provide, except for infrequent communications to resolve issues that may arise with your own ACR account. More routine announcements are made in our periodic newsletter, rather than via email.

Authentication Cookies - Our website uses cookies for authentication once you logged in as a member. The cookie is required to use the password protected area of the website. The authentication cookie is saved on your browser for the duration of the logged in session and deleted once you log out.

Additionally, we use session variables to aid in the development of various features on the site. These session variables disappear after 20 minutes or when the user exits a browser. Thus, this information is not stored for any reason other than as indicated.

We may also use personal information in a manner that does not identify you specifically nor allow you to be contacted but does identify certain criteria about our users in general. For example, we may inform third parties about the number of registered users, number of unique visitors, and the pages most frequently browsed.

Aside from these uses of user information - and we have no knowledge of this information except at an anonymous level - we do not sell, nor plan to sell any user information to anyone.

**Google Analytical**

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google, Inc. (“Google”). We enabled Google Analytics anonymization of IP addresses as soon as technically feasible at the earliest possible stage of the collection network. Learn more from their Terms of Service and Privacy Policy. Opt-out: Download the browser plugin “Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on” here.

If you choose to share our website pages using third-party social media buttons those services might be creating cookies in your browser.

**Protection of Children's Personal Information**

ACR is a general audience site and does not knowingly collect any personal information from children. While our website may be viewed by children, we do not wish to receive data from children. ACR encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the interactive activities offered on the sites their children visit. No information should be submitted to, or posted at, the ACR web site by visitors under 18 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian.

**Links to Third Party Sites**

This website contains links to other web sites that are not controlled by ACR ("Third Party Sites"). Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. The ACR Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by this website.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

ACR will occasionally update this privacy policy. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the privacy policy. For material changes to this statement, ACR will notify our users by placing prominent notice on the site.

**Enforcement of this Privacy Policy and Contact Information**

ACR welcomes your comments regarding our privacy policy.

IF FOR ANY REASON YOU BELIEVE THAT YOUR PRIVACY HAS BEEN BREACHED THROUGH THE USE OF OUR SITE, YOU MAY CONTACT US IMMEDIATELY BY E-MAIL, [acr@acrwebsite.org](mailto:acr@acrwebsite.org) AND WE WILL DO OUR BEST TO PROMPTLY DETERMINE AND CORRECT THE PROBLEM.
